# **Junior García**

Full-Stack Web Developer

jrgarciadev.com github.com/jrgarciadev +541122559178 jrgarciadev@gmail.com hashnode.com/@jrgarciadev

Software Developer, specializing in building exceptional websites and mobile applications with 4 years involved in the whole software development life cycle providing IT solutions for private and public organizations using React.js, React Native, Next.js, Vue.js and Laravel. I like creating and contributing to open-source projects as well as blogging.

## **Relevant Experience**

## Full-Stack Developer @ Ecomerciar

April 2019 - Present | Buenos Aires, AR

- Communicate and collaborate with multi-disciplinary teams of engineers, designers, producers, clients, and stakeholders on a daily basis.
- Write modern, performant, and robust code for a diverse array of client and internal projects.
- Work with a variety of different languages, frameworks, and content management systems such as JavaScript, TypeScript, React, React Native, Vue, Laravel, Node.js, Strapi, etc.
- Developed company website and loading time improvement by 40% also improve user experience.
- Mentored current junior software engineers on software engineering best practices.
- Clients included Mercado Libre, Tienda Nube, Glovo, Chazki, Renault, and more.
- Developed Android application using Java and Kotlin to process payments and sell from a Ingenico Axium D7 tablet in Argentina used by more than 5k merchants.
- Reduce by 30% the administrative operational costs related to packaging shipments by Tienda Nube sellers in Argentina by creating a plugin in Symfony and React.js that allows sellers to integrate Glovo to their stores and thus save costs and deliver packages in less than 1 hour.

## **Java Software Developer** @ Intelix Synergy

July 2017 - April 2019 | Valencia, VE

- Applied clean code practices and design patterns to develop a maintainable and scalable code for a in-house Cash Register Application
- Created new code and improved existing flow using SOLID design principles.
- Developed a module for client search and signup, using Java Swing components
- Worked closely with QA and management team to develop, document, and manage the Cash Register version 2 for Salvador country using MySQL, Java 8, and JPA
- □ Interfaced with clients on a weekly basis, providing technological expertise and knowledge
- Developed a JavaFX desktop application to manage stores setups saving 60% of spent time on manual configuration
- Contributed to improve code coverage by 50% by designing unit and integration tests.

#### **Skills**

# **Programming Languages**

**Strong:** JavaScript (ES6), TypeScript, HTML, CSS/Sass, GraphQL, PHP, Java. **Experienced:** Kotlin, Less.

#### **Libraries & Frameworks**

**Strong:** React, React Native, Android, Expo, Vue, Next.js, Node.js, Apollo, Express, Laravel.

**Experienced:** Symfony, Nuxt.js, Ionic.

#### **Databases**

**Strong:** MongoDB, MySQL, SQLite, Room.

Experienced: PostgresQL, DB2

#### **Tools & Platforms**

Git, Android Studio, Webpack, Vercel, Heroku, Strapi, Docker, AWS, Firebase.

## **Projects**

# CargoMe

Mobile app built with React Native, to connect truck drivers with companies to pickup cargo and deliver it according to their location.

# Nimble

Mobile app and administration panel built with React Native and Laravel to purchase in restaurants from a mobile phone without getting up from the chair or calling a waiter.

#### **Education**

Electrical Engineering, Universidad de Carabobo VE (2013 – 2018) - 7th semester approved.

## **Certifications**

Smart Checkout Integration - Mercado Libre

App development career with React Native - *Platzi* 

Backend development career with Php - Platzi

#### **Interests**

Swimming, traveling, blogging, reading.